Hi, I am Ananth Yadav from Jaunpur,
Uttar Pradesh. Currently,
I am pursuing my B.Tech from IIT,
Billai in Data Science and Artificial Intelligence.
So, let's head to the project. Okay.
So, I'll first, yeah,
I'll first start my virtual moment.
So, thereby, all I need to like a a
a a a so, yeah, the scripts and then then I don't
actually activate,
yeah, so, yeah, so, thereby, we started our moment.
Now, the next thing is simply we run our server.
So, let's head to our web page.
Okay, so, that's it.
Okay, so, just to make it from the scratch,
what I'll do that I'll try to open
this on the new window. So, let's do this.
Okay, so, I'll introduce incognito.
So, yeah. So,
this is how a piece looks like.
I'll drop this down. Okay,
so, if I start, this is a simple page.
I'll simply record it and yeah,
it asks me permission. Then I'll start and I'll allow it.
Okay, so, I think yeah, connect it.
So, let's start saying something and
yeah, I think it's working right now,
right? So, it's it's actually working and we have
some performance metrics too,
to measure how good it is or not.
So, yeah. So, let's just close it for now and so,
just for the sense, since our clear text is working or not,
we cleared this text and thankfully it's working.
Let's try it again. So, it should write connected.
Okay, great. Then, it should right now print something.
Yeah, go ahead. Okay. So, yeah,
it's writing. Okay. So, let's just close for now and let's just move
to our code,
walkthrough of our code. So, this is our webpage,
which basically includes all the HTML files that you just seen.
Django provides that same thing.
So, this is our simple webpage. What it is,
it's just having simple headers and some some
p tags and some buttons,
the record, record, close, or clear text.
So, this is ah where so this is our basically
our home page you see that and then we have our static folder
under the css we have some css styling you can see there okay i'll
make this down okay so we have some css too and then we have
our javascript which are which is our main folder which is actually containing what
is so i'll may give a basic workflow whether what is thing so this
is just for the counter that since we want only 90 seconds it
to store so this is for that thing and then we have we are
asking the permission and simply yeah this is our this
is the standard thing and then this this is where we are creating our
socket and once the socket is created we are just simply as
soon as we receive any message we are updating our values
in in the real time.
At the user level.
Okay, then we have some functionality like transcript what
will do and then we have a close connection what it has to do.
Okay, so then the most important thing whether how do we are actually
implementing it. So, before going further I will first make a quick walkthrough
of what we are actually doing. So, this this will help us.
So, you see this that this is a ah this is how our workflow
will going to be. User ah will have that render page which you have
just seen now. So, what is that user the the audio will come
from user to ah to it it will go to the ah Django
server which act which handles the socket computer as soon as the it as
soon as it receives the stream data it sends that stream data to the
Deep API. What it does, this DEPRAM API this
DEPRAM API then transcribe that data and
ah and then ah we get back to our transcribe data which where
Django server once it receives it simply sends that to user browser data and
which we get rendered. Okay,
so that's the basic workflow and I'll explain you a simple part.
You know what in order to ah you in order to do this ah
we had to use ah web software.
Since it is a real-time,
so we have our ASCII, we had to use ASGI way
tool for this and as such you can see that there are some custom
built-ins that need to be configured to use this ASGI.
ASGI and then we have our
consumer.py which what is actually it is using this DeepGram API and it
is then first it is trying to connect to our DeepGram API
and as soon as this is connecting this is simply asking ah asking ah
the ah this getinscript transcript function to render
for all the time until the connection is getting close.
So, it is rendering it is ah receiving the data and trying to send
it to the user .
Then we have our disconnected receive function.
So, this was all about this we have the routing functions too.
So, this was all about ah how the code work through before I
end up I will try to see some of the challenges that I faced
they include the django channels I didn't I
had to learn about this django channel so the documentation helped me to learn
about this django channels along with that uhm yeah
this we have to I wanted to know how this we can do this
real time so thankfully tibgram API helps to do this
directly as such and this page this wonderful page this helped me a lot
because they have used they have given the documentation even that how can we
do live transcription with Python and Django I had to make some changes in
order to receive that so that was the helpful for part for me alright
then we have also calculated the transcription latency
so I'll just make a quick walkthrough to that as well so
that is how we are actually calculating so even dbram api
helps us to give that thing so here we what we do that we
are basically calculating that transcription latency because that
need to be configured and we basically contributing
that time that ah the time that is ah that it is taking to
ah render the audio data ah my
ah difference by the one the total time taken by it.
So, that was one and accuracy that how accurately
it is able to determine that word that is already given in the ah
Dibram API as well. So, that helps a lot.
So, this was all about the code and our code is also deployable
to Vercel. So, yeah that was about our project.
Okay, I hope that helps.